Guide to the Outdoor Advertising Association of America (OAAA) Archives, 1885-2017 and undated RL.00963
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- ORGANIZATION -COMMITTEES SERIES, 1925-1984
  - Committee on Central and South America
    - Papers on Central and South America, 1947 Dec. 3 (H.E. Fisk) (Box CM2 -Letter Size)
  - Compensation Committee
    This committee covered issues ranging from salaries to depreciation of office equipment and billboard structures, along with Federal Highway Act audits regarding the cost of constructing new poster panels and billboard structures to comply with Highway Beautification Act guidelines of the early 1970s.
    - Papers, 1971-1973, 2 folders (Box CM2 -Letter Size)
      [ Compensation-evaluation committee; salaried personnel; audit by FHWA; confidential audit; requisition for supplies, service and shipments; comparative cost; brochure-production of a poster panel.]
    - Compensation Valuation, 1974-1981 (Box CM3 -Letter Size)
      [Correspondence; new release; payment schedule; Acquiring your real property for federal-aid highway -brochure 1975; compensation battle-FHWA (Federal Highway Administration); charts]
  - Coverage and Capacity Subcommittee
    - Agenda and Discussion Material, 1953, (H.B. Markham, Chairman) (Box CM3 -Letter Size)
  - Defense Mobilization Committee
    This committee dealt with wartime advertising and national security programs, such as for Defense Bonds, along with postwar manpower and materials requirement studies; for more information see the Issues and Activities series sections on World War II and Public Service campaigns.
    - Papers, ca. 1940-1956 (Box CM3 -Letter Size)
      [ Defense Mobilization Organization; U.S. Defense Bonds campaign; Public Relations; Business Development; Market Research and Development; glossary of terms]
    - Defense bond program, 1951. (Box CM3 -Letter Size)
  - Dues Review Committee
    - Papers, 1965 (Box CM3 -Letter Size)
  - Engineering Research and Development Committee
    - Recommendations, 1959 (Box CM3 -Letter Size)
  - Evaluation Committee
    An ad hoc committee that was set up in the 1930s to establish standards for evaluating the quality of poster service to advertisers.
    - Report, 1938 (Box CM3 -Letter Size)
  - Executive Committee
    This committee was responsible for issues of general association management, along with industry-wide concerns such as pending legislation and analyses of the legislative environment in various states.
    - Memos, 1942-1956 (Box CM3 -Letter Size)
      [Sources of business; new service rules and regulations for painted display; traffic audit bureau; support of government in war effort; subscription price for postal regulation; period of cancellation; operation improvement; Outdoor Advertising News; cooperation between AFA and AAA; etc.]
    - Officers, 1949-1953 (Box CM3 -Letter Size)
    - Papers, 1971-1981, 3 folders (Box CM3 -Letter Size)
      [Minutes of meetings; summary of actions of Executive Committee; meeting agendas; energy crisis]
  - Executive and Membership Committees
    - Combined Minutes, 1927-1929 (2 bound volumes) (Box CM3 -Letter Size)
  - Finance Committee (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
    This committee oversaw finance matters, including budgets, financial statements and general accounting issues.
    - Meeting, 1955 Oct. 25-26 (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
    - Memoranda, 1947-1958 (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
    - OAAA Special Committee on Dues and Finance, 1955 (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
    - Proceedings, 1959 (Bound volume) (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
  - Industry Relations Committee
    - Papers, 1965 (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
  - Legislative Committee
    This committee advised and interpreted pending legislation and its projected impact on the advertising industry, and recommended actions and counter-proposals for lobbying efforts.
    - Papers, 1987-1988. (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
      [Minutes, memoranda, article reprints, Ad Hoc Committee]
    - Legislation and Industry Relations Reports, 1938-1939, 2 folders (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
  - Market Research and Development Committee
    - Market Coverage Formula for Outdoor Advertising-Report, 1955 (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
    - Miscellaneous, 1957-1958 (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
    - Meeting, 1956 April 5-6 (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
      [A market coverage formula for outdoor advertising; report to the committee by F. Houston Wynn of Wilbur Smith and Associates; Formal report and recommendations resulting from meeting]
    - Report- Six Stages to Evaluate the Media, 1959 (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
    - Sample Preliminary Report, Waterloo, Iowa, 1956 (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
      [Market Research Project, confidential]
  - Membership Policy Committee
    This committee proposed and reviewed changes to Constitution and Bylaws, and resolved questions concerning membership.
    - Papers, 1976, 2 folders (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
    - Policy Report, 1964-1969 (Box CM4 -Letter Size)
      [Sections: 1. the problem; 2. current by-laws; 3. legal opinions]
  - National Advisory Committees (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
    The original National Advisory Committee formed a delegation that sat on the US Treasury Department National Advisory Council, created to oversee a variety of programs such as Defense Bonds and the U.S. Savings Bonds Program. Other advisory committees took part in advisory councils and boards to provide industry input on a variety of U.S. government policies, as reflected in the organizations' titles.
    - National Advisory Committee, 1940-1941 (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
      [Reports of meetings; recommendation of Public Relations Committee]
    - National Advisory Committee of the Outdoor Advisory Industry, 1941-1951 (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
    - National Advisory Committee on Highway Beautification, 1965-1966 (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
      This committee worked with the U.S. Department of Commerce's Bureau of Public Roads.
    - National Advisory Council and War Activities Committee-Joint Meetings, 1944-1945 (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
      These committees helped coordinate wartime advertising activities.
    - National Advisory Council Meeting, 1945 April 11-12 (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
      [Report on French Lick meeting; minutes of meeting; progress report on organization and program report of meeting]
  - Natural Resources Committee
    This committee worked with state planning departments.
    - Report -Status of City and County Planning, 1937 (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
  - Notre Dame Foundation Committee
    This committee oversaw the educational programs established at the University of Notre Dame, including the School of Outdoor Advertising.
    - Papers, 1951, 1965, 2 folders (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
  - Operating Standards Committee
    This comittee set policies for member operating practices, painted bulletin and billboard maintenance, and evaluated new techniques and technologies (paint, etc.). The committee also dealt with issues such as building codes, materials testing, and illumination techniques. Included are files on the Building Officials Conference of America; for related materials see the Physical Structure series.
    - Agenda Meeting, 1956 Nov. 12 (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
    - Building Officials Conference of America (BOCA)
      - 1947-1950 (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
      - 1950-1956 [Building codes] (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
    - Meeting Minutes of Standards Committee and National Conventions 1948-1950, 1935-1977, 2 folders (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
      [Also Macomb Business news journal 1940; TAB brochure 1977 with cover image from ca. 1910s]
    - Outline of Joint Meetings, 1952-1955, 2 folders (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
    - Papers, 1948-1949 (Box CM5 -Letter Size)
      [Original report of the Development and Research Department to the Operating Standards Committee, 1946-1947]
    - Papers, 1951-1954, 2 folders (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
      [ Fort Wayne and Cedar Rapids study 1954; Operating Standards Committee progress report 1952; reports and recommendations of the Operating Standards Committee and Subcommittees, 1953]
    - Papers, 1954 (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
    - Papers, 1955-1959 (Engineering Advisory Group.) (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
    - Papers, 1960 (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
  - Operations and Standards Committee
    - Papers, 1949-1984 (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
  - Organization Policy Committee
    - Meeting Program, 1940 (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
  - Organizational Review Committee
    - Committee Meeting, Washington D.C., 1970 June 17, [Confidential minutes; outline for meeting; envelope-paste-up; edited minutes; agenda] (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
    - Meeting Agenda, undated, [To consider recommendations of the Organizational Review Committee] (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
  - Out of Home Committee
    - Papers, 1990-1991 (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
  - Outdoor Advertising Committee
    - Meetings, 1949, 1952 (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
  - Painted Display Standards Committee
    - Committee Meeting, 1950 (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
  - Planning and Posters Committee
    - Report, undated (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
  - Plans Committee
    - Letter about meeting, 1959 (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
  - Plant and Service Committee
    - Papers, 1940-1958 (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
  - Plant Development Committee
    This committee treated issues concerning member plant operations, such as plant safety, building code requirements, standards for silkscreen and lithography, and combustibility studies. It also provided an interface between the Association and ANSI (American National Standards Institute) regarding structural construction standards.
    - Papers, 1972-1973, 2 folders (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
    - Report - The Standard Poster Panel and Reasons Why, 1940 (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
    - Technical Department, 1958 (Box CM6 -Letter Size)
    - Papers, 1974 (Box CM7 -Letter Size)
    - Papers, 1975 (Box CM7 -Letter Size)
      [Correspondence; A60 Standard; proposed revision of ANSI ( American National Standards Institute); procedures for management; agenda of Executive Standards Council; summary of actions of committee; minimum standards for Acrylic faces in internally illuminated outdoor signs; building code requirements for sign and display structures; letter ballot on proposed revision of ANSI A60.1; Tyvek; booklets-recommended operating practice; illumination standards for Outdoor Advertising Display 1959, minimum design loads in buildings and other structures 1955) (correspondence; energy saving lamps; standards for folding of poster paper by silk screen and litho printers; building code requirements for sign and outdoor display structures; report-OAAA Illumination Handbook draft; illumination standards; lighting committee; ANSI Procedures for Management and Coordination of American National Standards; folder-Specific Lighting Products]
    - Papers, 1976-1978, 2 folders (Box CM7 -Letter Size)
  - Poster Standards Committee
    This committee set and evaluated standard poster panel sizes and sheet configurations.
    - Discussion Memorandum, 1955 (Box CM7 -Letter Size)
      [For the Poster Standard Committee Relating to the Problem of a Dual Standard of Copy Area for Standard Poster Panels; Exhibit K concerns Photo-Graphic Eye-Camera]
    - Miscellaneous, 1945-1957, 2 folders (Box CM7 -Letter Size)
    - Problem of Standard Poster Panels, 1955 (Box CM7 -Letter Size)
  - Post-War Planning Board
    [This committee dealt with the reversion of outdoor advertising resources to peace-time operations.]
    - Post-War Planning Board, 1945 (Box CM7 -Letter Size)
  - Public Policy Committee (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
    This committee dealt with issues of public policy and voluntary regulation. It drew up model legislation and reviewed pending legislation, and issued statements regarding Association positions on public policy issues.
    - Clean-up/Paint-up/Fix-up Program, 1953 (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
    - Manual of Public Relations Practice, 1950 (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
    - Meetings, 1951-1952 (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
    - Meetings, Proposals, Regulations, and Reports, 1930s (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
    - Meetings and Recommendations, 1948-1949 (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
    - Meeting, Legislative Matters, Manual, and Recommendations, 1948-1949 (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
    - Meetings, Proposals, Regulations, Report, 1930s (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
    - Policy Statement, Meetings, and Recommendations, 1933-1939 (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
    - Policy Papers, 1950s (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
    - Public Policy Program and Manual, 1949 (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
    - Publication, You and Your Public, 1952 (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
    - Recommendations, 1951 (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
  - Public Relations Committee
    This committee worked to improve the image of outdoor advertising by working with outside interest groups; it also coordinated industry competitions and awards.
    - Committees, 1958-1959 (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
      [Public relations; contests and awards]
    - Meetings, 1925-1927 (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
      [Proceedings of Luncheon Meeting, Committee on Public Relations Cooperating with the OAAA]
    - Meetings, 1928-1930 (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
      [ 1928 Sept. 27 Fifth Conference, Organized Outdoor Advertising Industry, Committee on Public Relations]
    - Meetings, 1963 (Box CM8 -Letter Size)
    - Meetings, Recommendations, and Manual, 1940 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Miscellaneous, 1940-1957 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Public Relations Program and Manual, 1949-1950, 2 folders (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Recommendations, 1959 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Recommendations and Policy, 1930s (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Reports, Proceedings, Policies, and Proposals, 1930 & 1940 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Reports and Publications, 1929-1930 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
      [ Modern Outdoor Advertising-Its Policies and Practices, ca. 1930]
  - Reorganization Committee
    - Report of Committee on Reorganization Plans, 1946 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
  - Research Advisory Committee
    - Papers, 1960-1976 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Poster Appraisal Service Report of Progress, 1963 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
  - Review and Plan Committee
    This was a task committee set up to study OAAA's overall organizational structure, and proposed ways to streamline the organizational chain. The committee was responsible for, among other things, the creation of the Chairman's Advisory Committee as a standing committee with executive authority, and was the originator of the proposal to merge OAAA with OAI (which finally took place in the 1970s).
    - Letter asking for total gross billing, 1959 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Meeting, 1957 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Report on ownership of Association buildings, 1960 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Meeting, 1957 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Reports on Public Policy and Audit Procedure, 1961 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Standard Circulation Values of Outdoor Advertising by TAB, 1938 (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
      [The following 10 folders are organized in their original order.]
      [(From original box, folder 1 of 10) (box-Review and Plan Committee (outline on cover indicated Activity: A-Poster and Painted Display statistical Records and Service is missing; Standard Circulation Values of Outdoor Advertising by TAB 1938; Memorandum on Reconciliation: Reasons for and results of the Review and Plan Study of the activities and organization setup of the Association and related matters; Summary of Recommendations to the Review and Plan Committee based on the review an devaluation reports; Status of Subjects Referred to the Review and Plan Committee of The OAAA (Action: Subject: Proposed by: Status)
      Review -Evaluation Report on Activities:
      1-Business Relations Area: Activity: B-Local Business Development Program
      1-Business Relations Area: Activity: C-Traffic Audit Program
      1-Business Relations Area: Activity D-Market and Traffic Evaluation Research Projects
      2-Engineering, Research and Development
      3-Public Relations Area: Public Relations Activities
      4-General Administrative Area: Activities: Executive and Administrative)]
    - Memorandum of Reconciliation, 1959, (from original box, folder 2 of 10) (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Summary of Recommendations, 1959, (from original box, folder 3 of 10) (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Status of Subjects Referred to the Review and Plan Committee, 1959, (from original box, folder 4 of 10) (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Evaluation Report on Activities, 1959, (from original box, folder 5 of 10) (Box CM9 -Letter Size)
    - Evaluation Report on Activities, 1959, (from original box, folders 6-10 of 10) (Box CM10 -Letter Size)
    - Memorandum of Reconciliation, 1959, (from original box, folder 1 of 9) (Box CM10 -Letter Size)
      [The following 9 folders are organized in their original order.]
      1-Memorandum on Reconciliation Reasons for and Results of the Review and Plan Study of the Activities and Organizational Setup of the Association and Related Matters
      2-Summary of Recommendations to the Review and Plan Committee
      3-Status of Subject Referred to the Review and Plan Committee of the OAAA as of 1959 Sept. 8
      4-Review-Evaluation Report on Activities 1-Business Relations area; Activity: A-Poster and Painted Display Statistical Records and Service
      5-Review-Evaluation Report on Activities 1-Business Relations area; Activity: B-Local Business Development Program
      6-Review-Evaluation Report on Activities 1-Business Relations area; Activity: C-Traffic Audit Program
      7-Review-Evaluation Report on Activities: 1-Business Relations Area: Activity D-Market and Traffic Evaluation Research Projects
      8-Review-Evaluation Report on Activities: 2-Engineering, Research and Development Area
      9-Review-Evaluation Report on Activities: 3-Public Relations Area: Public Relations Activities)
    - Summary of Recommendations, 1959, (from original box, folder 2 of 9) (Box CM10 -Letter Size)
    - Status of Subjects Referred to the Review and Plan Committee, 1959, (from original box, folder 3 of 9) (Box CM10 -Letter Size)
    - Evaluation Report on Activities, 1959, (from original box, folders 4-9 of 9) (Box CM10 -Letter Size)
  - Safety Committee
    This committee set policies for workplace safety, to ensure compliance with OSHA regulations.
    - Accident Studies, 1938-1955, 2 folders (Box CM10 -Letter Size)
    - OAAA Safety Manual, 1974, [Spiral bound manual; correspondence] (Box CM11 -Letter Size)
    - OAAA Safety Manual, ca. 1974 (Box CM11 -Letter Size)
    - OSHA -Occupational Safety and Health Administration, 1978-1979 (Box CM11 -Letter Size)
    - OSHA correspondence, 1973-1988 (Box CM11 -Letter Size)
      [ An Employer's Guide to the Occupational Safety, Health Administration's Switch to Common Sense Priorities; Administrative law judge's opinion; Federal Register]
    - OSHA File-OSHA Survey, 1980-1990 (Box CM11 -Letter Size)
      [Booklet-American National Standard for Ladders-Fixed-Safety Requirements]
    - OSHA Related Materials, 1970-1973, 2 folders (Box CM11 -Letter Size)
    - OSHA Settlement, 1976 (Box CM11 -Letter Size)
      [Posner (legal settlement; correspondence; failure of law to zero in on the problem-men wearing the safety belts provided)]
    - Papers, 1972-1977, 2 folders (Box CM11 -Letter Size)
  - Sectional Committee
    - Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box CM11 -Letter Size)
  - Sign Inter-Association Committee
    - Papers, 1940-1947 (Box CM11 -Letter Size)
      [ American Highway Sign Association; Advertising Metal Sign Manufacturers Association; HR 49115 Randolph amendment-Federal-Aid Highway Act of 1944; Outdoor Advertising and Sign Industry Conference; commendation adopted-small signs and tack signs along highways in rural areas]
  - Special Standards Committee (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
    [See also Box CM16]
    - Emblem of Good Practice, 1963 (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
      [metal emblems included in folder]
    - Papers, 1961-1963 (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
  - TAB Task Committee
    - OAAA Task Committee Continuing Audit System; Suggested Procedures for Plants, ca. 1959 (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
  - Technical Committee
    - Reports, 1948 (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
  - Traffic Safety Coordination Committee
    - Reports, 1947-1949 (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
  - Urban Ordinance Committee
    This committee worked with the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) on a project to develop urban aesthetics programs to improve the urban visual environment. The committee was later renamed the Urban Planning Committee (files in this collection 1979-1982).
    - Communication Design Study
      - Cooper-Lecky, 1972-1979 (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
        [The Kent Cooper partnership; correspondence; DOT memo; notes of field trips- Robbinswood, Twin Cities, Donnelly, Baltimore, Tuscaloosa Ala., Atlanta Ga.]
      - Cooper-Lecky-Miscellaneous, brochures, 1977 and undated (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
      - Cooper-Lecky Publications, 1976-1977, 2 folders (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
      - Design Study Proposal, 1973 (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
        [Spiral booklet- A Proposal to the National Endowment for the Arts; regular bound materials-Urban Communications Design Study: scope of work; resumes]
      - Expo, 1982 (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
        [Expo in Knoxville, Tenn.; slides of Coca-Cola Santa posters; 5 test programs brochure; marketing and testing; Urban Planning Committee; 2 spiral bound brochures]
    - Court Case, Deer Park presentation, ca. 1972 (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
    - Court Case, San Diego [Calif.] presentation, 1973, (vol. vii) (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
    - Federal Beautification Legislation, Detailed History, undated (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
    - Industry Criticism, undated (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
    - Meetings and Reports, 1974-1975 (Box CM12 -Letter Size)
    - Ordinance Problems, Recognition and Handling, undated (Box CM13 -Letter Size)
    - Papers, 1973-1974, 4 folders (Box CM13 -Letter Size)
    - Papers and Correspondence, 1975, 2 folders (Box CM13 -Letter Size)
    - Papers and Correspondence, 1976, Folders 1-2 of 3 (Box CM13 -Letter Size)
    - Papers and Correspondence, 1976, Folder 3 of 3 (Box CM14 -Letter Size)
    - Public Relations Support Correspondence, 1971 (Box CM14 -Letter Size)
    - Rebuttal to Street Graphics, 1973 (Box CM14 -Letter Size)
    - Sales Testimonials, 1971-1973 (Box CM14 -Letter Size)
    - Urban Ordinances Comparisons, undated (Box CM14 -Letter Size)
    - Urban Ordinance Kit, 1973-1976 (Box CM14 -Letter Size)
      [Report-model ordinance-1 slide; outline of federal outdoor advertising legislation and congressional history; draft of pilot ordinance; San Diego ordinance; rebuttal to book Street Graphics]
    - Witnesses, Selection and Usage for Public Hearings, undated (Box CM14 -Letter Size)
  - Urban Planning Committee
    - Correspondence, 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box CM14 -Letter Size)
    - Papers, 1979-1982 (Box CM14 -Letter Size)
  - Washington Steering Committee
    - Papers, 1957-1964 (Box CM14 -Letter Size)
      [File of D.W. Vanderwater (correspondence; article copies; Department of Commerce Bureau of Public Roads; remarks of Harry O'Mealia, Jr. of OAAA at joint OCDM-OAAA press conference; meeting notices; etc.)]
    - Papers, 1968-1970 (Box CM14 -Letter Size)
      [Correspondence; news clippings-Billboard Man Pushes Plan to Remove Billboards, The Myth of the Highway Trust Fund; amendments to the Beautification Act]
  - Women's Organizational Advisory Council
    This was an updated form of the Women's Auxiliary Committee (files in this collection 1939-1941 - see box CM16). The women's auxiliary committee was originally formed to recognize women's contributions to outdoor advertising and to provide women in outdoor advertising with a vehicle for creating networks among women professionals.
    - Papers, 1960-1961 (Box CM14 -Letter Size)